Guide to the Benoit Mandelbrot Papers M1857
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 26. Audiovisual Material
  - Green Room, WFMU Dorian Devins (audiocassette), 1998-04-27 (Box AV-14, Item 29)
  - Le Monde Change, Benoit Mandelbrot (audiocassette), 2000-06-28 (Box AV-14, Item 30)
  - Interview with Dr. Benoit Mandelbrot, Re: Norbert Wiener. Flo Conway & Jim Seligman. Tape 1 of 2 (audiocassette), 2000-07-08 (Box AV-14, Item 31)
  - Interview with Dr. Benoit Mandelbrot, Re: Norbert Wiener. Flo Conway & Jim Seligman. Tape 2 of 2 (audiocassette), 2000-07-08 (Box AV-14, Item 32)
  - BBC Radio 4. Frontiers (1/6): Econophysics. Week 17. Tx: Wednesday 25th April 2001. (audiocassette), 2001-04-25 (Box AV-14, Item 33)
  - [Dche pi] Lorentz. RAI - Radio 3 (audiocassette), 2001-06-14 (Box AV-14, Item 34)
  - Oche di Lorenz. Milano (audiocassette), 2001-11-23 (Box AV-14, Item 35)
  - Lecture at Cornelia Street Café (audiocassette), 2002-09-01 (Box AV-14, Item 36)
  - Mandelbrot 1/3 Stockholm (audiocassette), 2002 (Box AV-14, Item 37)
  - Mandelbrot 2/3 Interview in English, talks about his work in finance (audiocassette), [2002] (Box AV-14, Item 38)
  - Mandelbrot 3/3 (audiocassette), [2002] (Box AV-15, Item 1)
  - Lecture Budapest in French (audiocassette), 2003-10-14 (Box AV-15, Item 2)
  - Interview Knack, Brussels 2004 (interviewer: Joel De Ceulaer) joel.de.ceulaer@knack.be (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 3)
  - Urania-Vortrag, Fraktale und Finanzen - Markte zwischen Risiko, Rendite und Ruin. Prof. Dr. Benoit B. Mandelbrot (audiocassette), 2005-05-03 (Box AV-15, Item 4)
  - Herve Provini: "Musiques chaotiques". 1o Musique chaotique I, 1o Musique fractale I. 2o usique chaotique II 2o Musique fractale III (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 5)
  - No 1. T. M. Couter, RC, T.N (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 6)
    Many more notes in Japanese
  - No. 2 RC, Couter, 661 T.N (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 7)
  - Conference Benoit Paris (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 8)
  - AAAS Meeting. San Francisco / Biological Geometry, Part 2. (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 9)
    [looks like second part of tape AV14-005]
  - Individual Intaview [sic] by Kyodo News (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 10)
    [Additional notes on cassette case in Japanese]
  - Individual Intaview [sic] by Nihon Keizai Shimbun. Talk Tokyo Hotel Japan Prize week (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 11)
  - Individual Intaview [sic] by Chunichi Shimbun (Tokyo Shimbun) (audiocassette), 2002 (Box AV-15, Item 12)
  - Botanica (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 13)
  - N. Z. Z. Book Review. Translation. (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 14)
  - INFOVOX SA-101 Multilingual Text-to-Speech Unit. English French German Spanish Italian Swedish (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 15)
  - [no title] (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 16)
  - Mandelbrot 1/2, Mandelbrot 2/2 (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 17)
    "Palais de la Decouverte. Very interesting exposition of Mandelbrot's fractal theory"
  - Fractal Music, Gary Jwo - John Bowne HS, Flushing, N.Y. 11367. I. Rubinstein - Research Coordinator (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 18)
  - A.) Harri Vuori: "The Mandelbrot Echoes", Finnish Radio Symphony Orch., Cond. Sakari Oramo (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 19)
  - Benoit Mandelbrot. Ralph Losey 407-841-7470, Box 285 Orlando Fl 32802 (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 20)
    [additional info on cassette case]
  - R[T]HK 'Fractals' (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 21)
    "Interview Hong Kong"
  - Mandelbrot 1 (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 22)
    "Interview in French, good descriptoin of early life & IBM & adolescence"
  - Mandelbrot 2 (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 23)
  - David Ortega, 16425 Harbor Blvd #276, Fountain Valley, CA 92708, (714) 839-2392 (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 24)
  - Mandelbrot interview 2A (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 25)
  - You & Eye Documentaires Fance inter, Savez-vous ce qu'on ne sait pas? Un emission concue et presentee par Frederic Allinne (audiocassette) (Box AV-15, Item 26)
    "Fractals about halfway through the tape"
  - 100M DLA L (Video8) (Box AV-16, Item 1)
  - 100M DLA P (Video8) (Box AV-16, Item 2)
  - 100M DLA D (Video8) (Box AV-16, Item 3)
  - 100M DLA HIJ (Video8) (Box AV-16, Item 4)
  - 100M DLA 4/27/93 (cat7rmt0) (Video8), 1993-04-27 (Box AV-16, Item 5)
  - 100M DLA A (Video8) (Box AV-16, Item 6)
  - 100M DLA B (Video8) (Box AV-16, Item 7)
  - 100M DLA C (Video8) (Box AV-16, Item 8)
  - 70M DLA (Video8) (Box AV-16, Item 9)
  - 100M DLA HIJ (Video8) (Box AV-16, Item 10)
  - 100M DLA MNO (Video8) (Box AV-16, Item 11)
  - BANDHI BACKUP - "PUT ME BACK!" (Video8) (Box AV-16, Item 12)
  - 100M DLA K (Video8) (Box AV-16, Item 13)
  - BANDHI:/U/HEPTING/SIGGRAPH/* (Video8) (Box AV-16, Item 14)
  - 130M DLA D (GNU tar) (Video8) (Box AV-16, Item 15)
  - DLAs: 1-15M 16-1M (Video8) (Box AV-16, Item 16)
    DLA Archive: 1 15M particle DLA. 16 1M particle DLAs
  - 100M DLA (film reel) (Box AV-16, Item 17)
  - Fractal Structure of a Diffusion Front. B. Sapoval, M. Rosso, J. F. Gouyet, J. F. Colonna (film reel), 1985 (Box AV-16, Item 18)
  - [Zeam?] "Aggregation" (film reel) (Box AV-16, Item 19)
  - Phycomyces blakesleeanus (Mucorales) Vegetative Life Cycle. Final 1. 129m. E2159. Encycloapedia Cinematographica. (film reel), 1975-04 (Box AV-16, Item 20)
    April 1975 Final
  - 1st. Julia Set Metamorphosis. Blue blanking, no leader (film reel) (Box AV-16, Item 21)
  - 2nd. Zooming In on the Mandelbrot Set. 16mm. No blanking, numbered leader. (film reel) (Box AV-16, Item 22)
  - Powers of Ten. Print number 1742 020041 (film reel), 1978 (Box AV-16, Item 23)
  - Graphics Lab. "Dynamical Systems", Uni Bremen. Prel. Zoom into Sea horse valley. Status 25.10.86. -noncontinuous transition between animation sections. - bug in interpolation. - bug in frame si. RB Prod.-No. 681/117. AFGA-Positiv (film reel) (Box AV-16, Item 24)
    Address: Hartmul Juirgens, FB3 University of Bremen, Bibliothekstr. 7, 2800 Bremen 33
  - First version poorly exposed (film reel) (Box AV-16, Item 25)
  - #2 (film reel) (Box AV-16, Item 26)
  - #3 (film reel) (Box AV-16, Item 27)
  - #8 (film reel) (Box AV-16, Item 28)
  - Untitled (film reel) (Box AV-16, Item 29)
    [title taken from film reel] "Clustering in Three Dimensions Using Sample Functions of Paul Levy Motions"
  - OXTON #10 (film reel) (Box AV-16, Item 30)
  - #9 (film reel) (Box AV-16, Item 31)
  - [no title] (film reel) (Box AV-16, Item 32)
  - [no title] (film reel) (Box AV-16, Item 33)
  - I (1/4 inch audio tape) (Box AV-16, Item 34)
  - II (1/4 inch audio tape) (Box AV-16, Item 35)
  - [no title] (1/4 inch audio tape) (Box AV-16, Item 36)
  - IBM Works and Progress. 15 IPS. N. R. No. Doves 2 & 3. Audio 1 & 2. AVL Cues Eagle on 3. Clock on four. Heads out. (1/4 inch audio tape), 1990-04-20 (Box AV-16, Item 37)
    "Heads Out. Gug 2A. Doves 2 & 3 Start at 5. No tonestart right at leader. 15 IPS trk 3 positrak, trk 4 clok"
- Series 27. Computer Media/Born-digital Material
  The material contained in this series consists of documents, graphics, spreadsheets, databases, software programs, and other material created and/or stored on computers managed by Mandelbrot's research assistants. The digital files are forensically captured images of those stored on hard drives, floppy diskettes, CD-ROMs, zip disks, and other media in the Benoit Mandelbrot papers.
  Also included is one half-box with paper-based material that accompanied loose computer media.
  Materials are available on the Media Cart in the Special Collections Reading Room.
  - "Fractal Witchcraft" - program flyers and instructions; removed from CM_158 and CM_159 (floppy diskettes) (Half-box 533, Folder 1)
  - Housing for "Personally Developed Software for IBM Personal Computers. Mandelbrot Set Exploration Tool"; removed from CM_11 and CM_12 (floppy diskettes) (Half-box 533, Folder 2)
  - Housing for "The Desktop Fractal Design Handbook"; removed from CM_13 (floppy diskette) (Half-box 533, Folder 3)
  - Housing for "Fractal Magic"; removed from CM_115 and CM_116 (floppy diskettes) (Half-box 533, Folder 4)
  - Letter and notes; removed from CM_119 (CD "Site Oscillo-Fract") (Half-box 533, Folder 5)
  - Letter removed from CM_168 (DVD, documents for archive) (Half-box 533, Folder 6)
  - Letter; removed from CM_234 (floppy diskette, "Fractals") (Half-box 533, Folder 7)
  - Letter; removed from CM_102 (floppy diskette, "Powers of Ten Interactive") (Half-box 533, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters; removed from CM_103 – CM_106 (floppy diskettes, "FRAC'Cetera") (Half-box 533, Folder 9)
  - Notes; removed from CM_107 (floppy diskette, "Book N") (Half-box 533, Folder 10)
- Series 28. Restricted Material
  The materials in this series are restricted until January 1, 2045.
  This series consists of material removed from the collection due to privacy and confidentiality concerns. The records are arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Restricted - American Academy of Arts and Sciences nomination form, 2003 May 30 (Box 327, Folder 1)
  - Restricted - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - nominations, correspondence, 1985-1991 (Box 327, Folder 2)
  - Restricted - Applications/resumes of others (Box 327, Folder 3)
  - Restricted - Confidential letter, 1988 Dec 13 (Box 327, Folder 4)
  - Restricted - CVs, applications of others (Box 327, Folders 5-6)
  - Restricted - Dean reappointment letter, 2002 (Box 327, Folder 7)
  - Restricted - Financial documents (Box 327, Folders 8-9)
  - Restricted - Financial documents - invoices, receipts, timesheets of assistants (Box 327, Folder 10)
  - Restricted - Harvard resignation letter, 1987 (Box 327, Folder 11)
  - Restricted - Household bills (Box 327, Folder 12)
  - Restricted - Human resources - Anton Amann, 1995 (Box 327, Folder 13)
  - Restricted - Human resources - BBM (Box 327, Folder 14)
  - Restricted - Human resources - others (Box 327, Folder 15)
  - Restricted - "IBM Confidential" - expense reports for Fractals Department, 1988-1989 (Box 327, Folder 16)
  - Restricted - "IBM Confidential" - expense reports for Fractals Department, 1988-1989 (Box 328, Folder 1)
  - Restricted - IBM employee information/applications/agreements (Box 328, Folders 2-3)
  - Restricted - Insurance - France (Box 328, Folder 4)
  - Restricted - invoices with social security numbers (Box 328, Folder 5)
  - Restricted - letter of recommendation for Michael Frame, 1993 (Box 328, Folder 6)
  - Restricted - letter regarding student's behavioral problem, 1985 Jun 10 (Box 328, Folder 7)
  - Restricted - letters of recommendation, grant evaluations, referee reports, 1960s-1980s (Box 328, Folders 8-13)
  - Restricted - letters of recommendation, grant evaluations, referee reports, 1960s-1980s (Box 329, Folder 1)
  - Restricted - letters of recommendation, 1970s-1980s (Box 329, Folder 2)
  - Restricted - letters of recommendation, human resources/personnel files, 1970s-1980s (Box 329, Folder 3)
  - Restricted - letters of recommendation, referee reports, grant evaluations, 1990s (Box 329, Folder 4)
  - Restricted - letters of recommendation, referee reports, grant evaluations, 2000s (Box 329, Folder 5)
  - Restricted - Lesh, Susan, 1993 (Box 329, Folder 6)
  - Restricted - Math 195 - Fractals, Randomness and Survey - course list, Harvard, 1984-1985 (Box 329, Folder 7)
  - Restricted - NSF proposals for BBM review, 1985 (Box 329, Folder 8)
  - Restricted - NSF proposals for BBM review, 2007 (Box 329, Folder 9)
  - Restricted - Pacific Northwest National Lab - hiring packet, 2005 (1 CD "Fractal Dynamics Dec 2005 - Pacific Northwest National Laboratory" has been removed from this folder and placed in the computer media series for forensic capture) (Box 329, Folder 10)
  - Restricted - Pacific Northwest National Lab - hiring packet, 2005 (1 CD "Fractal Dynamics Dec 2005 - Pacific Northwest National Laboratory" has been removed from this folder and placed in the computer media series for forensic capture) (Box 329, Folder 11)
  - Restricted - Personal/confidential correspondence, 1960s (Box 330, Folder 1)
  - Restricted - Personal/financial documents (Box 330, Folder 2)
  - Restricted - Pickover/Leonardo, 1993 (Box 330, Folder 3)
  - Restricted - Postdoc applications, 1990 (Box 330, Folder 4)
  - Restricted - Recommendations - Richard Voss (Box 330, Folder 5)
  - Restricted - Refereeing, 1983 (Box 330, Folder 6)
  - Restricted - "Referees of papers IER, 1960; Econ 1961; Orr; Zanfaller[?]; Beter; review of Hudson, 1959-1965" (Box 330, Folder 7)
  - Restricted - research assistant/secretarial/typist invoices and checks, 1997-1998 (Box 330, Folder 8)
  - Restricted - retirement/pension information, 2008 (Box 330, Folder 9)
  - Restricted - documents containing social security numbers (Box 330, Folder 10)
  - Restricted - student grades (Box 330, Folder 11)
  - Restricted - student papers (Box 330, Folder 12)
  - Restricted - tax documents, 1940s (Box 330, Folder 13)
  - Restricted - tax documents, 1950s (Box 330, Folder 14)
  - Restricted - Academy nominations, circa 2000-2004 (Half-box 495, Folder 1)
  - Restricted - Academic papers, referee comments, circa 1996-1997 (Half-box 495, Folder 2)
  - Restricted - Miscellaneous references for jobs, graduate school, tenure and promotions (Box 496, Folders 1-6)